MOSES MAJIWA

P. O. BOX 32053 - 00600

NAIROBI, KENYA PHONE: 0722631909

EMAIL: moses.majiwa@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL HIGHLIGHTS

A highly self-motivated professional who thrives well even in high-pressure work environments. Exceptional team player who appreciates the importance of cultural diversity in the modern work environment. Appreciates goal-oriented challenges, has a keen eye on quality and systematic approach to problem solving processes. Interested in the application of technological innovations in providing sustainable solutions to real life problems. Keen on imparting experience and knowledge in the development of future human capacity who will influence and change the world for better.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Management and leadership of team members in delivery of work targets
- Resolved internal and external stakeholders management issues that can affect project timelines
- Effective time management skills and collaboration with key stakeholders, working assiduously to meet deadlines.
- Demonstrated ability to lead multiple medium to large scale projects simultaneously while effectively meeting all deadlines and budgets
- Ability to analyze, understands and logically breakdown complex business requirements
- Strong attention to details in analysing and execution of tasks
- High level communication and presentation skills exhibited in working in different multinational companies and across cultures
- Collaborated with project sponsor and key stakeholders in developing project initiation documents outlining the scope, goals, deliverables, required resources, budget and project timeline.
- Great expertise in the procurement and efficient utilization of project materials and other resources.

COMMUNICATION AND TEAMWORK

- Highly motivated self-starter with ability to multitask and complete assignments within time constraints and deadlines
- Effective communication skills both written and oral
- Strong interpersonal skills with a high degree of maturity, diplomacy, and professionalism
- ❖ Demonstrable ability in team development, management, and consensus-building
- Team player who inspire and motivate team members during any given assignment
- Established and maintained effective working relationships with management, employees and business partners.
- Embraces cultural diversity and appreciates contribution of multiculturism in the modern work environment.

TECHNICAL CAPABILITIES

- Proficient in MS Project, MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Visio
- Proficient in Matlab and Simulink for power systems simulation
- Proficient in the use of eQUEST for modelling energy utilisation in buildings
- Proficient in the use of RETScreen for Energy & Financial Analysis of Renewable Energy projects
- Power Systems Simulator (PSS/ADEPT) for analysis of Power Distribution systems,
- Power Systems Simulator for Engineering (PSS/E) for analysis of Power Transmission Systems,

- Power Builder 2019,
- Structured Query Language (SQL), Procedural Structured Query Language (PL/SQL),
- SNMPc Network Management System
- Prince2 Project Management skills
- Foundation knowledge of ITIL IT Service Management Methodologies

EDUCATION					
03/2015 06/2016	to	Master of Electronic & Energy Engineering (MElecEnergyEng) Griffith University, Nathan Campus. Brisbane, Australia Specialization: Traditional Power Systems, Modern Power systems, Sustainable Energy technologies and Energy Efficiency. Research project: Home Automation using Raspberry Pi.			
05/2009 04/2014	to	Master of Business Administration [Double concentration] United States International University – Africa, Nairobi, Kenya Special interest areas – Strategic Management and minor in Information & Communications Technology.			
04/1992 11/1996	to	Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture & Technology Special interest areas – Industrial Technology and Systems Engineering.			
1987 - 1990		Attained Grade B- (Minus) in the second lot of Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education [KCSE] Examinations			

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

30th October Kenya Power & Lighting Company Ltd

2018 - Current Senior Engineer

Power Systems Telecommunications – Central Office, Fiber Infrastructure Unit Head

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ Provide leadership and management of the Fiber infrastructure Unit in Power Systems Communications section.
- ✓ Take custody of the over 6,000km Fiber Optic cable infrastructure of the company
- ✓ Oversee the Design, development & growth of the Fiber Optic cable network as a critical Telecommunication infrastructure for the company
- ✓ Oversee the Operations and Maintenance of the existing Fiber Optic Cable Network Infrastructure to guarantee 99% availability.
- ✓ Champion of ISO 9001:2015 Quality Management System in the department to guarantee quality assurance of processes and hence service delivery to both internal and external customers.
- ✓ Lead Auditor & Trainor, ISO 9001:2015 Quality Management System

1st September Kenya Power & Lighting Company Ltd

2016 – 29th 1st Assistant Engineer

October 2018 Power Systems Telecommunications – Central Office, Projects

- ✓ Design and development of Telecommunication infrastructure including Fiber Optic cable network
- ✓ Project Management for the development of 1300km of Fiber Optic Cable infrastructure and Management of the existing Fiber Optic Cable Network Infrastructure.
- ✓ Champion of ISO 9001:2008 Quality Management System in the department to guarantee quality assurance of processes and hence service delivery to both internal and external customers.

August 2014 - Australia for UNHCR, Brisbane, Australia

August 2016 Team Leader (Casual)

Fund raising activities for the recruitment of long-term donors into the Emergency Response Team with Australia for UNHCR in aid of helping to alleviate the pain and suffering of the people displaced by conflicts and natural disasters under the umbrella of UNHCR worldwide.

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ Inspiring the Australian public in Queensland to make regular donations towards alleviating the pain and suffering of the people displaced by conflicts and natural disasters under the umbrella of UNHCR worldwide.
- ✓ Managing and Leading units of fundraising teams in discharging their duties, motivating and helping individual team members to achieve their targets.
- ✓ Assisted the Campaign Manager with the launch of the door to door fundraising program in Queensland.
- ✓ Assists the Campaign Manager with the management and regular assessment of the door to door fundraising program in Queensland.
- ✓ Assisting the Campaign Manager with the identification and evaluation of new fundraising opportunities in Queensland.
- ✓ Assisting the Campaign Manager with the identification of talents among the fundraising team members and helping to develop team members

July 2014 – BioSolar Australia PTY Ltd, Brisbane, Australia
December Lead Generator – Sales Consulting Agent (Casual)

Sales and Installation of solar photovoltaic systems [Solar Panels, Racking's and inverters] in residential and small businesses.

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ Acting as lead generation representative in the promotion and marketing of Solar Photovoltaic systems
- ✓ Securing appointments with prospective customers [home owners] through lead generation activities
- ✓ Attend by-weekly lead generation meetings
- ✓ Liaise with installation teams on after sales service with clients
- ✓ Make proposals for the improvement of lead generation activities
- ✓ Make suggestions on product sales and marketing strategies

October 2012 - Kenya Power & Lighting Company Ltd

June 2014 1st Assistant Engineer

Power Systems Telecommunications – Central Office, Projects

- ✓ Managed the design, procurement and installation of 650km of ADSS Fiber Optic Cable on the Medium and Low voltage electrical power networks to connect Key substations, facilities and offices for data communications, tele protection, SCADA use as well as lease to third parties. Project cost = Kshs 300Million
- ✓ Assistant project Manager for the implementation of Distribution Network Automation project in Nairobi Region.
- ✓ Ensure compliance to Electrical Safety Rules in all Telecommunications and ICT projects in proximity to electrical power lines.
- ✓ Overseeing the transformation in the Broadband infrastructure business on KPLC Low voltage Power Distribution Network. Account management of the KPLC Broadband infrastructure business.

January 2009 - Kenya Power & Lighting Company Ltd

September **2**nd **Assistant Engineer**

2012 Power Systems Telecommunications – Central Office, Projects

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ In 2011 I was appointed the project coordinator for the Transformer Intruder Detection System (TIDS) Pilot project which achieved 70% vandalism deterrence on 23 transformers attacked out of the 1000 protected transformers in its first six months of implementation saving the Kshs 8M in direct costs on the potential loss of the saved transformers. The pilot project ended on 31st March 2013 and is to be rolled out nationwide.
- ✓ Reformed the modus operandi and methods of construction for Broadband Infrastructure Operators licensed by KPLC to use its Low Voltage Power Distribution Network for construction of cable to the home.

July 2003 – Kenya Power & Lighting Company Ltd

January 2009 Data Networks Engineer

Data Networks Telecommunications - Central Office, Nairobi

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ In 2008 I participated in the KPLC Wide Area Network Upgrade and Extension using VSAT technology to facilitate the corporate goal within the precincts of the Branch Empowerment Program. Led the team in Coast region in connecting 10 sites through VSAT.
- ✓ In 2007 I participated in the migration of the KPLC Wide Area Network (WAN) from static routing to dynamic routing. I led the West Kenya Team in installation of various network devices in 20 offices that facilitated the practical application of the concept.
- ✓ Managed the KPLC Data networks using Network Management and Monitoring system SNMPc.
- ✓ Implemented various key projects in Data Networks telecommunications.

August 2002 - Soluziona Kenya Ltd

June 2003 **Business Development Executive**

In charge of a five (5) member team responsible for business development activities for Information Systems Management consultancy in the Utilities sector.

✓ Was instrumental in securing a contract for modernization of the revenue collection system at the Nairobi Water and Sewerage Company Ltd.

September Soluziona Zimbabwe (PVT) Ltd 2001 – July Management Consultant

2002 Vision 2000 ICS Project – Zimbabwe Electricity Supply Authority (ZESA)

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ Was charged with leading a team of seven members responsible for the System Implementation and Data Collection Campaigns for the Integrated Customer Services (ICS) system in all ZESA Areas.
- ✓ Developed work plans for the team members based on the project work plan and monitored the progress ensuring that targets are met.
- ✓ Assisted team members to achieve their targets whenever there was need.
- ✓ Participated in the analysis of the current customer service business trends in ZESA within the scope of project objectives.
- ✓ Participated in the preparation of the ICS conceptual design and system functional scope based on the current situation analysis.
- ✓ Coordinated the quality checks on data collected prior to conversion of the same.

January 2001 – Soluziona Zimbabwe (PVT) Ltd August 2001 Management Consultant

Vision 2000 IMS Project – Zimbabwe Electricity Supply Authority (ZESA)

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ Was charged with leading a team of four members responsible for data Collection, Data Conversion, Training and Implementation of the Incidence Management System (IMS) system in all ZESA Areas.
- ✓ Developed work plans for the team members based on the project work plan and monitored the progress ensuring that targets are met.
- ✓ Assisted team members to achieve their targets whenever there was need.
- ✓ Participated in the analysis of the current customer service business trends in ZESA within the scope of project objectives.
- ✓ Participated in the preparation of the IMS conceptual design and system functional scope based on the current situation analysis.
- ✓ Coordinated the Data collection, quality checks and conversion of customer, secondary substation and other installations data into the IMS System.
- ✓ Developed documentations for the IMS System, trained users and rolled out the system as well as providing user support.

August 2000 – Soluziona Zimbabwe (PVT) Ltd
December Junior Management Consultant

2000 Vision 2000 IMS Project – Zimbabwe Electricity Supply Authority (ZESA)

- ✓ Lead member of a team responsible for data Collection for the Incidence Management System (IMS) system in all ZESA Areas.
- ✓ Developed data collection methodology, procedures and tools.
- ✓ Conducted training for data collection personnel in all ZESA Areas.
- ✓ Managed and coordinated the data collection and data entry processes.
- ✓ Carried out data quality control of collected data.

July 1999 – July IberAfrica Systems Ltd

2000 Junior Management Consultant

Institutional Strengthening Project (ISP) – Kenya Power & Lighting C. Ltd (KPLC)

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ Participated in the Development of the Distribution and Transmission Network Improvement plan. (DTNIP) and there after developed proposals for the optimization of the Transmission, Subtransmission and Distribution network.
- ✓ Analyzed the historical faults in the Medium Voltage Distribution Network with the assistance of the historical faults data in the Incidence Management System (IMS).
- ✓ Modeled and conducted a study of the Electricity Transmission and Sub-Transmission network using the Power Systems Simulator for Engineering (PSS/E).
- ✓ Modeled and conducted a study of the Medium Voltage Electricity Distribution network using the Power Systems Simulator Advanced Distribution Productivity Tool (PSS/ADEPT).
- ✓ Participated in the adaptation of the Medium Voltage Network to the defined Medium Voltage Network Architecture rules.

June 1997 - Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture & Technology [JKUAT]

June 1999 Tutorial Fellow

Department of Mechanical Engineering

Key Responsibilities

- ✓ Taught and examined diploma students in Fluid Mechanics, Industrial Metrology and Materials Science.
- ✓ Examined diploma students' final year projects.
- ✓ Developed laboratory-training manuals in Machine Vibrations and Computer Numerical Controlled (CNC) Machines.
- Represented the department of Mechanical Engineering in the Faculty of Engineering Committee on Postgraduate Studies and Research plans in the year 2000 and Beyond.
- ✓ Member of the Steel and Aluminium Standards Technical committee of the Kenya Bureau of Standards in charge of formulating standards on steel and aluminium structures.
- ✓ Coordinated and organized the 4th and 5th Mechanical Engineering Annual Seminars in 1998 and 1999 respectively, hosted by the Department of Mechanical Engineering.

PROFESSIONAL INVOLVEMENT

2011 - 2016 Member of the Journal Committee of the Institution of Engineers of Kenya charged with publishing of the Kenya Engineer magazine.

2012 – 2013	Member of the	Advocacy committee of the Inst	itution of Engineers of Kenya		
2004 – 2011	2004 – 2011 Member and Secretary of the Conference Committee of the Institution of Engineers Kenya charged with organizing and coordinating the Annual Engineers conference				
PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP					
2017 to Date					
2016 to Date	16 to Date Inducted by IEEE as Graduate Member: IEEE Member Number 93943591				
2015 to Date	Inducted by the	Member: EA ID 5306308			
2012 to Date Inducted by the Engineers Board of Kenya as a Professional Graduate Engineer					
1998 to Date Graduate Member of the Institution of Engineers of Kenya					
COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT					
2018 – Date					
2018 – Date	Tournament Dir Chair, Match & I Convenor, Discip	a Hockey Union (KHU) Irnaments			
		um Sub Committee a & Publicity Sub Committee			
2014 - 2016	Member of the Brisbane African Seventh-day Adventist church in charge of Men's Ministries as well as advisor to the Personal Ministries council.				
2013 - 2014	Member of the Strategy and Governance committee of the Nairobi Hockey Association				
2012 - 2014	2012 – 2014 Convener of the strategic committee of Wazalendo Hockey club				
2010 - 2016 Founder Director of Young Players Development program at Wazalendo Hock charged with implementation of social transformation through Field Hockey in the neighbourhoods of the club					
2004 - 2016					
2004 – 2008					
2002 – 2004	2002 – 2004 Chairman, Central Management Committee, Wazalendo Hockey Club				
REFERENCES					
Eng. Joseph Ka	riuki,	Eng. Daniel Kiniti	Dr. Prasad Kaparaju,		
County Busines		Chief Engineer, Power	Lecturer, Renewable Energy Systems		
KPLC Nyandaru	_	Systems Communication	Griffith School of Engineering		
P O Box 244 – 2		Kenya Power	170 Kessels road		
	20300,	•			
Nyahururu	22004	P. O. Box 30099 – 00100 Nairobi	Nathan QLD 4111		
Cell: +254 7263	Australia				
Email: Kariukij@	укріс.со.ке	Cell: +254 711279235	Cell: +61 437 092 944		

Email: dkiniti@kplc.co.ke

Email: p.kaparaju@griffith.edu.au